Mirelda Diker

Business Analyst

🔾 Ontario, CA 🗷 mireldadiker@gmail.com 📞 +1 437 871 7316 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirelda-diker/ 🔘 https://github.com/Mirelda

PROFILE

As a Business Analyst with three years of experience, I have gained knowledge in various areas during my studies, but have not specialised in any particular area. Currently, I am focusing on developing my skills in backend development through projects. With a wide range of knowledge and experience in data and business analysis, I aim to improve business processes and increase efficiency. I am flexible, open to learning and thrive in a collaborative environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst, SmartPulse Technology Inc.

07/2021 - 12/2023

Orchestrated comprehensive analyses of the energy market to drive strategic developments, leveraging Miro charts for visual representation and enhancing PowerBI reports for actionable insights; optimized Azure environments and supported various application tools to drive business growth.

- Development and presentation of screens for the management of consumption portfolios to the production market management
- Development of integration modules and ensuring ease of use by 3rd party users.
- Providing analysis studies to apply the SSO Structure to the portal
- Compiling and organizing test processes on the Azure platform and making it a tradition

Data Analyst, SmartPulse Technology Inc.

05/2020 - 08/2020

Analysis of energy market data to identify wind imbalance situations and development of a forecasting algorithm to increase regional concentration of renewable energy production, efficiency and load income

• Decomposition of region-based power plants on the map of Turkey and verification of their locations and development of production forecasting algorithms by increasing the accuracy of weather forecast clarity

Product Consulting / Analyst, Hitsoft

10/2021

I managed a freelance project focusing on screen analysis and marketing strategies. Working with a dynamic team, I used my analytical skills and creative thinking to develop innovative approaches in line with the project's objectives. This initiative allowed me to hone my skills in market research, strategic planning and project management, delivering impactful results in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment.

SKILLS

Data Visualization/Analysis Web Design **Microsoft Office** Analyst HTML / CSS / JavaScript Excel | Word/ PowerBI Miro/Azure/MSSQL/Virtuoso Python/ R

UI/UX Figma

EDUCATION

Computer Engineering Department, Çukurova University 2017 - 2022

Full Stack Software Developer, Lambton College 01/2024 - present

LANGUAGES

English Turkish Intermediate Native

ORGANIZATIONS

CENGA, General Coordinator *⊗* 2019 - 2022

CENGA is a volunteer-based computer engineering association at Cukurova University. It organises events, courses and activities. It hooks up with companies and provides opportunities for students to have a knowledge about the sector.

2017 - 2022 CUHAYDOST, Accountant Coordinator

A club made up of animal lover friends where we meet the shelter, nutrition and health needs of all the animals around us.

REFERENCES

Hande Aydemir, Product Director, SmartPulse haydemir@smartpulse.io

Mehmet Fatih Akay, Prof. Dr.

fakay2004@gmail.com

Bülent Bedir, Director Of Research Development, Hitsoft

bulent.bedir@hitsoft.com.tr